Guide to the Julie Gilbert Papers ca. 1940-1998 MSS 38 MSS.038
Fales Library and Special Collections
- Series I: Printed and written research materials, 62489
  - Sotheby's re: Frida Kahlo tray, 1979; 62618 (Box 5, Folder 294)
  - Sotheby's contract for Kahlo tray, 1980; 62617 (Box 5, Folder 295)
  - Sotheby's re: Diego Rivera, 1984; 62616 (Box 5, Folder 296)
  - Obituaries, 1990; 62615 (Box 5, Folder 297)
  - Research, business, 1945; 62614 (Box 6, Folder 298)
  - Research, business, 1946; 62613 (Box 6, Folder 299)
  - Research, business, 1947; 62612 (Box 6, Folder 300)
  - Research, business, 1948; 62611 (Box 6, Folder 301)
  - Research, business, 1949; 62610 (Box 6, Folder 302)
  - Research, business, 1950; 62609 (Box 6, Folder 303)
  - Research, business, 1951; 62608 (Box 6, Folder 304)
  - Research, business, 1952; 62607 (Box 6, Folder 305)
  - Research, business, 1953; 62606 (Box 6, Folder 306)
  - Research, business, 1954; 62605 (Box 6, Folder 307)
  - Research, business, 1955; 62604 (Box 6, Folder 308)
  - Research, business, 1956; 62603 (Box 6, Folder 309)
  - Research, business, 1957; 62602 (Box 6, Folder 310)
  - Research, business, 1957; 62601 (Box 6, Folder 311)
  - Research, business, 1958; 62600 (Box 7, Folder 312)
  - Research, business, 1959; 62599 (Box 7, Folder 313)
  - Research, business, 1960; 62598 (Box 7, Folder 314)
  - Research, business, 1960; 62597 (Box 7, Folder 315)
  - Research, business, 1961; 62596 (Box 7, Folder 316)
  - Research, business, 1962; 62595 (Box 7, Folder 317)
  - Research, business, 1963; 62594 (Box 7, Folder 318)
  - Research, business, 1964; 62593 (Box 7, Folder 319)
  - Research, business, 1965; 62592 (Box 7, Folder 320)
  - Research, business, 1966; 62591 (Box 7, Folder 321)
  - Research, business, 1967; 62590 (Box 7, Folder 322)
  - Research, business, 1968; 62589 (Box 7, Folder 323)
  - Research, business, 1969; 62588 (Box 7, Folder 324)
  - Research, business, 1970; 62587 (Box 7, Folder 325)
  - Research, business, 1971; 62586 (Box 7, Folder 326)
  - Research, business, 1973; 62585 (Box 7, Folder 327)
  - Research, business, 1974; 62584 (Box 7, Folder 328)
  - Research, business, 1975; 62583 (Box 7, Folder 329)
  - Research, business, 1976; 62582 (Box 7, Folder 330)
  - Research, business, 1979; 62581 (Box 7, Folder 331)
  - Pryor, Cashman, Sherman and Flynn, legal files, undated; 62580 (Box 7, Folder 332)
  - Pryor, Cashman, Sherman and Flynn, legal files, undated; 62579 (Box 7, Folder 333)
  - Photos from Fales collection, undated; 62578 (Box 7, Folder 334)
  - Reproductions of early photos of Paulette G., undated; 62577 (Box 7, Folder 335)
  - Photo duplications, undated; 62576 (Box 7, Folder 336)
  - Photo duplications, undated; 62575 (Box 7, Folder 337)
  - Photo duplications, undated; 62574 (Box 7, Folder 338)
  - Individual interview with Alpert, Warren, undated; 62573 (Box 8, Folder 339)
  - Letter of understanding with Monika Anderson, Apr 12, 1992; 62572 (Box 8, Folder 340)
  - Individual interview with Albu, Ruth, undated; 62571 (Box 8, Folder 341)
  - Individual interview with Bellosta, Paula, undated; 62570 (Box 8, Folder 342)
  - Dietrich- Steve Bach article, undated; 62569 (Box 8, Folder 343)
  - Individual interview with Bach, Steven, undated; 62568 (Box 8, Folder 344)
  - Blackglama, undated; 62567 (Box 8, Folder 345)
  - Individual interview with Bach, Steven- Dietrich book, undated; 62566 (Box 8, Folder 346)
  - Individual interview with Bellosta, Antoinetta, undated; 62565 (Box 8, Folder 347)
  - Dietrich, Marlene obituaries, undated; 62564 (Box 8, Folder 348)
  - Individual interview with Dunham, Ella, undated; 62563 (Box 8, Folder 349)
  - Blue Angel- The Life of Marlene Dietrich excerpt re: Remarque, undated; 62562 (Box 8, Folder 350)
  - Freedom of Information Act, undated; 62561 (Box 8, Folder 351)
  - Individual interview with Fantoni, undated; 62560 (Box 8, Folder 352)
  - Frazier, James Re: Paulette, 1938; 62559 (Box 8, Folder 353)
  - Individual interview with Fairbanks, Douglas, undated; 62558 (Box 8, Folder 354)
  - Filmographies of EMR and PG, undated; 62557 (Box 8, Folder 355)
  - Individual interview with Gerard, Rolf, undated; 62556 (Box 8, Folder 356)
  - Individual interview with Goldsmith, Henry, undated; 62555 (Box 8, Folder 357)
  - Individual interview with Granato, Lois, undated; 62554 (Box 8, Folder 358)
  - Individual interview with Gavin, John and notes from various periods, undated; 62553 (Box 8, Folder 359)
  - Individual interview with Habe, Licci, undated; 62552 (Box 8, Folder 360)
  - Individual interview with Hau, Michael, undated; 62551 (Box 8, Folder 361)
  - Individual interview with Horlitz, Margaret- Felix Guggenheim's secretary, undated; 62550 (Box 8, Folder 362)
  - Individual interview with Kay, Richard, undated; 62549 (Box 8, Folder 363)
  - Kirkus bio. Review (bad), 1995; 62548 (Box 8, Folder 364)
  - Photograph of The Lancia (puma), undated; 62547 (Box 8, Folder 365)
  - Individual interview with Lantz, Robert, undated; 62546 (Box 8, Folder 366)
  - Letters from Robert Lantz to EMR, July 3 and Sept. 8, undated; 62545 (Box 8, Folder 367)
  - Anita Loos, 1973; 62544 (Box 8, Folder 368)
  - Individual interview with McCrary, Jinx Falkenburg, undated; 62543 (Box 8, Folder 369)
  - Individual interview with McKay, Gardner, undated; 62542 (Box 8, Folder 370)
  - Individual interview with Mankiewitz, Joseph, undated; 62541 (Box 8, Folder 371)
  - Individual interview with Meredith, Burgess, undated; 62540 (Box 8, Folder 372)
  - Individual interview with Murray, Helen, undated; 62539 (Box 8, Folder 373)
  - Individual interview with Morgenroth, Ruth Albu, undated; 62538 (Box 8, Folder 374)
  - Individual interview with Marton, Ruth, undated; 62537 (Box 8, Folder 375)
  - Individual interview with Nimoy, Leonard, 1973; 62536 (Box 8, Folder 376)
  - Hotel Nikolai- Osnabrück today, undated; 62535 (Box 8, Folder 377)
  - Osnabrück 1992- archive staff, 62534 (Box 8, Folder 378)
  - Osnabrück University, undated; 62533 (Box 8, Folder 379)
  - Paulette pictures, undated; 62532 (Box 8, Folder 380)
  - Individual interview with Rainer, Luise, undated; 62531 (Box 8, Folder 381)
  - Reiss, Curtis article in German translated by H. Goldsmith, undated; 62530 (Box 8, Folder 382)
  - Remarque, Jutta Zambona, undated; 62529 (Box 8, Folder 383)
  - Individual interview with Rigioria, Luciana, undated; 62528 (Box 8, Folder 384)
  - Individual interview with Riva, Peter Re: Dietrich, undated; 62527 (Box 8, Folder 385)
  - Individual interview with Roc, Patricia, undated; 62526 (Box 8, Folder 386)
  - Royalties 1986-1989, undated; 62525 (Box 8, Folder 387)
  - Second Chorus picture for advertising campaign, undated; 62524 (Box 8, Folder 388)
  - Sotheby's auction, undated; 62523 (Box 8, Folder 389)
  - Individual interview with Selznick, Daniel, undated; 62522 (Box 8, Folder 390)
  - Individual interview with Schneider, Thomas, undated; 62521 (Box 8, Folder 391)
  - Individual interview with Smithers, undated; 62520 (Box 8, Folder 392)
  - Individual interview with Stone, Peter, undated; 62519 (Box 8, Folder 393)
  - Villa Monte Tabor, undated; 62518 (Box 8, Folder 394)
  - Biography book parties, 1995; 62517 (Box 8, Folder 395)
  - Early attempt at source notes for biography, undated; 62516 (Box 8, Folder 396)
  - Individual interview with Wolf, Victoria, undated; 62515 (Box 8, Folder 397)
  - Individual interview with Wiese, Barbara, undated; 62514 (Box 8, Folder 398)
  - Individual interview with Wallis, Celestine, undated; 62513 (Box 8, Folder 399)
  - Will of Paulette Goddard Remarque, undated; 62512 (Box 8, Folder 400)
  - Filmography of EMR, miscellaneous information and Hollywood reporter's allegation re: Frida Kahlo, undated; 62511 (Box 8, Folder 401)
  - Individual interview with Zernik, Lotte, undated; 62510 (Box 8, Folder 402)
  - The Writer's Guide to Self-Promotion and Publicity By Elane Feldman, undated; 62509 (Box 8, Folder 403)
  - Krieg und Literature/ War and Literature v.1 n.1 4/1989, 62508 (Box 8, Folder 404)
  - Erich Maria Remarque 1898-1970 Rasch Velag Bramsche, undated; 62507 (Box 8, Folder 405)
  - Jahrbuch/Yearbook Erich Maria Remarque II/1992, 62506 (Box 8, Folder 406)
  - Krieg und Literature/ War and Literature v.1 n.2 1989, 62505 (Box 8, Folder 407)
  - Understanding Erich Maria Remarque Hans Wagener, undated; 62504 (Box 8, Folder 408)
  - Erich Maria Remarque: A literary and film biography, undated; 62503 (Box 8, Folder 409)
  - Erich Maria Remarque: Der Feind, undated; 62502 (Box 8, Folder 410)
  - Jahrbuch/Yearbook Erich Maria Remarque, undated; 62501 (Box 8, Folder 411)
  - Erich Maria Remarque Im Westen Nichts Neues, undated; 62500 (Box 8, Folder 412)
  - Erich Maria Remarque: a thematic analysis of his novels Peter Lang, undated; 62499 (Box 9, Folder 413)
  - Paulette: The Adventurous Life of Paulette Goddard by Joe Morella and Edward Epstein, undated; 62498 (Box 9, Folder 414)
  - Marlene Dietrich by Maria Riva, undated; 62497 (Box 9, Folder 415)
  - Charles Chaplin: My Autobiography, undated; 62496 (Box 9, Folder 416)
  - Memo from David O. Selznick ed. Rudy Behlmer, undated; 62495 (Box 9, Folder 417)
  - Showman: The life of David O. Selznick by David Thomson, undated; 62494 (Box 9, Folder 418)
  - Fate Keeps on Happening by Anita Loos, undated; 62493 (Box 9, Folder 419)
  - Sotheby's Magnificent Jewelry, April 1990, 62492 (Box 9, Folder 420)
  - Sotheby's Magnificent Jewelry, October 1990, 62491 (Box 9, Folder 421)
  - German language publications: Erich Maria Remarque by Rasch Verlag Bramsche; Erich Maria Remarque Friedenspreis der Stadt Osnabrück; Mitteilungen der Erich Maria Remarque Gesellechaft Osnabrück E.V., undated; 62490 (Box 9, Folder 422)
- Series II: Media, 62434
  - Brand: Maxell XLII Contents: Jinx Falkenberg McCrary, undated; 62488 (Box 10, Object cassette_1)
    Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements note
    Audiocassette
  - Brand: Maxell XLII Contents: Jinx Falkenberg McCrary, undated; 62487 (Box 10, Object cassette_2)
  - Brand: Maxell XLII Contents: Complete "Brown" book, "White" book, undated; 62486 (Box 10, Object cassette_3)
  - Brand: Maxell XLII Contents: White book conclusion, undated; 62485 (Box 10, Object cassette_4)
  - Brand: Supertape Extended Range Contents: Bob Collecello on Paulette, undated; 62484 (Box 10, Object cassette_5)
  - Brand: Memorex dBS Contents: Henry Goldsmith's translation of Remarque's early years, undated; 62483 (Box 10, Object cassette_6)
  - Brand: Memorex Contents: Henry Goldsmith's translation of early Remarque material, undated; 62482 (Box 10, Object cassette_7)
  - Brand: Maxell Contents: Henry Goldsmith's translation of Remarque's early life and career, undated; 62481 (Box 10, Object cassette_8)
  - Brand: Maxell UDII Contents: Henry Goldsmith translating transcript of Elfriede Remarque's trial, undated; 62480 (Box 10, Object cassette_9)
  - Brand: Panasonic MC-60 Contents: Julie Gilbert on Paulette Goddard, undated; 62479 (Box 10, Folder micro_1)
    Microcassette
  - Brand: TDK MC-60 Contents: Julie Gilbert on Paulette Goddard, undated; 62478 (Box 10, Folder micro_1)
  - Brand: Olympus XB60 Contents: Julie Gilbert on Dr. Bissig (Paulette's Doctor during the last years) Julie Gilbert on Luciana Riguron (local boutique owner), undated; 62477 (Box 10, Folder micro_1)
  - Brand: Panasonic MC60 Contents: Ruth Albu- third interview, undated; 62476 (Box 10, Folder micro_1)
  - Brand: Sony MC60 Contents: Dick Kay, 1991, 62475 (Box 10, Folder micro_1)
  - Brand: Panasonic RT-60MC Contents: #1 B. Wiese, Paulette's physical therapist, undated; 62474 (Box 10, Folder micro_1)
  - Brand: Panasonic RT-60MC Contents: #2 B. Wiese, Paulette's physical therapist, undated; 62473 (Box 10, Folder micro_1)
  - Brand: Panasonic MC 60 Contents: Bob Uhlman on Paulette, undated; 62472 (Box 10, Folder micro_1)
  - Brand: Certron Contents: Julie on Paulette, undated; 62471 (Box 10, Folder micro_2)
  - Brand: Certron Contents: Julie on Paulette, undated; 62470 (Box 10, Folder micro_2)
  - Brand: TDK MC60 Contents: Julie Gilbert on Paulette Goddard, undated; 62469 (Box 10, Folder micro_2)
  - Brand: Panasonic RT-60MC Contents: Julie Gilbert on Paulette Goddard, undated; 62468 (Box 10, Folder micro_2)
  - Brand: TDK MC60 Contents: Julie Gilbert on Paulette Goddard, undated; 62467 (Box 10, Folder micro_2)
  - Brand: TDK MC60 Contents: Bellosta, undated; 62466 (Box 10, Folder micro_2)
  - Brand: Sony MC60 Contents: Peter Stone re: EMR highspeed P.S. is a well known writer, undated; 62465 (Box 10, Folder micro_2)
  - Brand: Olympus XB60 Contents: D. Selznick (David O. Selznick's son) about Paulette, undated; 62464 (Box 10, Folder micro_2)
  - Brand: Certron Contents: Michael Hall Nove. 1991 Friend of P. Goddard's, 62463 (Box 10, Folder micro_3)
  - Brand: TDK Contents: Lois Granato, undated; 62462 (Box 10, Folder micro_3)
  - Brand: TDK Contents: Patricia Roc, undated; 62461 (Box 10, Folder micro_3)
  - Brand: TDK Contents: Celestine Wallis, undated; 62460 (Box 10, Folder micro_3)
  - Brand: Panasonic RT-60MC Contents: Lotte Zernik (knew EMR), undated; 62459 (Box 10, Folder micro_3)
  - Brand: Olympus XB Contents: Douglas Fairbanks, undated; 62458 (Box 10, Folder micro_3)
  - Brand: Olympus Contents: H.G. my dad, undated; 62457 (Box 10, Folder micro_3)
  - Brand: Panasonic Contents: Dick Kay, undated; 62456 (Box 10, Folder micro_3)
  - Brand: TDK MC-60 Contents: Sir and Lady Smithers, undated; 62455 (Box 10, Folder micro_3)
  - Brand: Olympus Contents: Robby Lantz, undated; 62454 (Box 10, Folder micro_3)
  - Brand: Olympus Contents: Helen Murray, undated; 62453 (Box 10, Folder micro_3)
  - Brand: Panasonic Contents: Paul Kohner's Secretary Paul Kohner was EMR's Hollywood agent, undated; 62452 (Box 10, Folder micro_3)
  - Brand: Olympus Contents: #2 Thomas Schneider, undated; 62451 (Box 10, Folder micro_3)
  - Brand: Olympus Contents: #3 Thomas Schneider, undated; 62450 (Box 10, Folder micro_3)
  - Brand: Olympus Contents: #4 Thomas Schneider, undated; 62449 (Box 10, Folder micro_3)
  - Brand: Olympus Contents: Paola Belosta, undated; 62448 (Box 10, Folder micro_3)
  - Brand: TDK Contents: Lois Granto, undated; 62447 (Box 10, Folder micro_3)
  - Brand: 3M Contents: Opposite Attraction, undated; 62446 (Box 10, Object Disk_1)
    Floppy disk
  - Brand: Bonus by Verbatim Contents: Remarque Wordperfect 5.1 Opposite Attraction, undated; 62445 (Box 10, Object Disk_2)
  - Brand: Verbatim Contents: Remarque 2 Wordperfect 5.1 Opposite Attraction, undated; 62444 (Box 10, Object Disk_3)
  - Brand: 3M Contents: Bellosta, Fairbanks, Kay, Lantz, Murray, Selznick, Zernik 1 and 2, undated; 62443 (Box 10, Object Disk_4)
  - Brand: Unlabeled Contents: Kay 2.51 Richard Kay, undated; 62442 (Box 10, Object Disk_5)
  - Bonus by Verbatim Wiese 1 and 2.51 Fanto 1.51 Fanto 2 and 3.51 Ger 1 and 2.51 Gold .51, undated; 62441 (Box 10, Object Disk_6)
  - Brand: 3M Contents: Dunham .51 Meredith .51 Hall .51 Rigbis .51 Horlitz .51 Roc .51 Mart 234.51 Smithers .51 Marton 1.51 Wallis .51, undated; 62440 (Box 10, Object Disk_7)
  - Brand: Bonus by Verbatim Contents: Habe 1.51 Habe 2.51 Rainer .51 Stone .51 Wolf .51, undated; 62439 (Box 10, Object Disk_8)
  - Brand: TDK MF-2HD Contents: Remarque Word Perfect 5.1 Dos IBM, undated; 62438 (Box 10, Object Disk_9)
  - Brand: TDK MF-2HD Contents: Remarque 4.6, undated; 62437 (Box 10, Object Disk_10)
  - Brand: Global Contents: Remarque Word Perfect 5.1 Part 1, undated; 62436 (Box 10, Object Disk_11)
  - Brand: Global Contents: Remarque Word Perfect 5.1 Part 2, undated; 62435 (Box 10, Object Disk_12)